Hi.
你好
I'm looking for a seed.
我在找一顆種子
Red, small.
紅色，小小的
A little seed, this big.
小小一顆，大概這麼大
Grows into a round plant,
長在環繞的植物上
this high...
這麼高...
Does it flower?
它會開花嗎？
No, you can't eat it.
不行，你不能吃它
The plant is about this high.
那個植物會長這麼高
Is it sold here?
在這裡有賣嗎？
I was told I could buy it here.
我聽說這裡可以買到
Where can I buy it?
哪裡可以買呢？
It's too late.
太遲了
Ok, thanks.
好吧，謝謝
Hi, I'm looking for a little red seed.
你好，我在找一顆紅色的小種子
A little seed.
一顆小種子
I don't know its name.
我不知道它的名字
What?
什麼？
No, that's not it. A seed.
不是，不是這個，是種子
That I'm falling?
我在往下掉？
That's why he's so fat.
這就是為什麼他這麼胖
During the day he barely eats.
他在白天幾乎不吃東西
His body goes on high alert.
他身體其實也發出警訊了
When he pigs out at night
他在半夜像豬一樣大吃時
his body thinks it needs to absorb everything.
他的身體認為他需要全部都吸收
So it's better to eat a little at a time.
所以少量多餐還是比較好
Are you listening?
你有在聽嗎？
Yes. All the way down?
有。一直往下走嗎？
Yes.
對
Know where it is?
你知道它在哪裡嗎？
No.
不知道
I'm hungry.
我好餓唷
Thanks.
謝謝
Why show my feelings if we never talk?
如果我們不交談，何必顯露我的情緒呢？
What're they doing?
他們在做什麼？
I think they're going out.
我想他們要出去了
No, guys like you.
不是，是那些像你一樣的傢伙
What do you mean?
你什麼意思阿？
I think I'll skip work tomorrow.
我想我明天會翹班
You always say that.
你每天都這麼說
Look, I cut my finger.
看！我切到手指了
That's normal.
這很正常阿
Normal for you, not for me.
對你來說很正常，對我不是
You drinking a beer?
你喝啤酒嗎？
Are you kidding? Obviously.
你在開玩笑嗎？ 當然阿！
I can't see, but I can smell it.
我看不出，但我聞的出
You can't see?
你看不到？
My eyes need to adjust.
我的眼睛需要一些調整
Let's play "Say it, win it!"
我們來玩[敢說就贏了]
You lie.
你說謊
What?
什麼？
He's a big liar.
他是個大騙子
It's no fun playing with you.
跟你玩一點都不好玩
My shoes!
我的鞋子！
Take them off.
把它們脫了
Let's order pizza. It'll do us good.
我們來叫比薩吧，這對我們好
Go for it.
好阿叫吧
Yep.
好耶
Cool.
酷
I dreamt air was like dough.
我夢見空氣就像麵團一樣
What?
什麼？
Bread dough.
做麵包的那種？
Raw?
生麵團？
And I destroyed myself to understand.
我為了搞懂這一切差點毀了自己
What are you doing?
你在做什麼？
Nothing.
沒有阿
Say it, win it.
說出來，你就贏了
I thought you were making fun of me.
我以為你在開我玩笑
Why show my feelings if we never talk?
如果我們不交談，何必顯露我的情緒呢？
I don't want to go.
我不想走
So what's your hurry?
那你在趕什麼？
No other openings.
沒有別家是開的
Oh well.
是阿
She's a bitch.
她真是個賤人
My shoulder hurts.
我肩膀痛死了
Look.
你看
Did she do that?
是她弄的？
Indirectly, yes.
間接的，算是
Sure this is the way?
你確定是這條路？
Vacation is no vacation
如果我一直做重複的事情，
if I keep doing the same thing.
假日就稱不上假日了
Are you listening?
你有在聽嗎？
Got the flowers?
拿到花了沒？
Yep.
嗯哼
Where'd you put them?
你把它們放在哪裡了？
Tell me.
快告訴我
Deep inside in total safety.
在很安全的深處
That way I'm sure they're safe.
這樣我才能確保它們是平安的
Spare me the details.
細節就不用說了
Want some?
要一些嗎？
No, thanks.
不用了，謝謝
What?
什麼？
That you should put it in the bag.
那你應該把它放在背包裡阿
Oh, I heard it, you said jungle.
我-聽-到-了，你說叢林
So, are you coming tonight ?
那所以，你今晚會來嗎？
I don't think so, I don't have any money.
我不覺得，我沒錢了
Don't worry, I'll lend you some.
又沒差，我借你阿
No, it's fine, if I don't have, I don't have.
不用啦，沒關係。如果我沒錢，就沒錢阿
Hey, Archie !
嘿Archie！
What's up?
你好嗎？
I'm good.
還不錯啦
Are you going this way?
你也往這邊嗎？
Yes, I'm coming home.
嗯，我正要回家
I forgot to tell I will stay out too late.
我忘記說我快遲到了
So where you with Kinny last night?
所以你昨晚跟Kinny在一起？
No ...
沒有...
He texted me that they were doing a party downstairs.
阿，他傳簡訊說他在樓下開啪踢
But I was already on my bed, eating cheese, drunk,
但我已經醉倒在我床上，還吃著起司
so I didn't feel like going.
所以我超不想去的
I turned off the phone, lights,
我關了手機，燈，
everything. I dissapeared.
所有的東西，像我消失了一樣
I think I'm getting old.
我覺得我在變老
So you're not coming tonight?
所以你今晚真的不來唷？
I don't think so.
應該不會
I think he wants to spend time with Alf and Bobby.
我覺得他比較想跟Alf 和 Bobby相處
Stop lying!
少在那邊亂講！
I bought a new plant. It's funny.
我買了一個新植物，它很妙
This tree is new too, right?
這些樹也是新的，對嘛？
Yes.
沒錯
And why is it funny?
那它妙在哪呢？
You never know how it'll act with you.
你猜不到它會怎麼跟你互動的
What's it called?
它叫什麼？
Armadillo tail.
犰狳尾
What's it do
它能做什麼？
Makes me want to see pictures of girls.
讓我想看女孩子的照片
Girls?
女孩子？
Yep.
對
Have you talked to Paul ?
你跟Paul講過話了嘛？
No
沒耶
Sorry
抱歉
I've not been able to talk to Paul
我一直沒辦法跟Paul講話
because I've got no light for some days now.
因為我已經有一陣子沒燈可用了
Ah, so you're still without light
蛤！所以你一直沒有燈唷！
Yeah, twenty days !
對阿，二十天了耶
Twenty days ?
二十天！
You can come to my house if you want.
你可以來我家阿，如果你想
Ok.
好哇
Mabel !
What are you doing here?
你在這裡幹嘛？
Hey! Where are you going?
哈囉！你要去哪裡？
I'm going to school, you ?
我要去學校阿，你呢？
I'm going to work.
我要去上班了
Oh, that's nice.
喔，那不錯阿
I don't know.
我不知道耶
You don't know what ?
你不知道什麼？
Going to work ...
要不要去上班阿...
Ok, come this way.
好，那你走這條路
Is it this way to your school ?
這是你去學校的路嗎？
No. I come here when I don't want to go to school.
沒有，我不想去學校的時候我才走這條路。
I want to learn music,
我想知道跟音樂有關的事情，
and download music.
然後也下載一些新音樂
You want?
你要嗎？
No.
不用
I'm ok.
我這樣就可以
In what could I specialize?
我應該專攻什麼呢？
Maybe you could work in a supermarket.
也許你可以在超級市場工作
Yes ! I will learn more about music there.
沒錯！我在那裡可以學更多音樂的知識（才怪）
In what could I specialize?
我該專攻什麼？
Are you listening ?
你有在聽嗎？
Doctor, I think this guy is lying.
教授，我認為這個人在撒謊
But it's not important.
但這並不重要
Really?
真的嗎？
Do we need to find a psychiatrist for him?
我們需要為他找一位心理醫生嗎？
Not that much.
也沒那麼誇張
Well, let's send him out.
叫他離開這裡
Please !
拜託你！
It's just a minute.
只要一分鐘就好！
I've got all the papers !
我所有的報告都寫好了
I won't come again,
我不會再來了
I swear.
我發誓
Was that already here? Is it new?
這本來就在這邊的嗎？這是新的嗎？
I need more money.
我需要更多錢
Soon.
快了
I still don't believe in reincarnation.
我還是不相信投胎輪迴
Ten more.
還有十個
Three...
三個...
Well... five.
好吧，五個...
Sleeping in the daytime isn't sleep.
做白日夢不算是睡覺阿
When I was little I said "dead" for "bed".
我小時候都把 "床" 說成 "亡"
Find the seeds?
找到種子了嗎？
Another time you might fall in love with me.
下一次，也許你會愛上我